Chapter 4: Foreground and Background

House elf magics appear to be based on a mechanism similar to that of accidental magic. Both of them override almost all warding systems, and both allow for power greater than that of many basic spells. Additionally, the possible spell effects available to either system are similar. However, the magic of house elves can be controlled by the wielder and directed.

Polyjuicing a house elf into a human form will succeed. The house elf will keep their magical ability and compulsions, and clothes in this form will still free the elf. One result discovered by testing indicates that among the magics that house elves can cast is a permanency effect which will extend the duration of a potion or effect for as long as the 'spell' is held. Experimentation on accidental magic has yet to confirm the presence of such an effect within the range of possibility, but it cannot yet be ruled out. Further experimentation in this area has been postponed until holding mechanisms for transformed elves can be devised. For further information, consult Appendix B, section C: Operation Epsilon.

Providing a wand to a house elf will greatly increase the power of their cantrips and decrease the cooldown time of their teleportations. However, any attempt to cast spells will fail and cause a magical backlash on the elf while activating their punishment compulsions. This seems to be an artifact of the spells laid on the elves. Further experimentation into this area has been discontinued pending the discovery of ways to override punishment compulsions.

House elves can be commanded to follow anything that a human mind can understand. House elves can understand commands from their master in any language. House elves can transmit commands from their master to any other elves that master controls provided they are so ordered. Further experimentation on this area has been postponed due to Protocol V.

-Research log, Appendix A: Postponed Experiments, Section III: Magical Creatures, Subsection I: House Elves(Tower of Hogwarts, May 1993)

XxX

September 1, 1993(Hogwarts opening day), 9 am

Colin strode through the platform, grinning as the magical warmth of the station replaced the cold outside. He was back. As he walked toward the train, Ginny came up alongside him, grinning.

"Colin!" She stood before him, smiling happily. She opened her mouth to say something, hesitated, then surprised him with a tight hug. Taking a step back, she blushed and picked at the hem of her sleeve. "It's nice to see you."

Colin's eyes widened.

"Y-you too," he stammered.

"Um...How was your summer?"

His eyes gleamed and he smiled.

"It's been excellent! I've found out so much about Sapespeck, and a few nights back I managed to get the network up and running-" He stopped talking as though he was punched in the throat, suddenly aware of what else had happened that night. Could he tell her? What would he even say? 'I think I might have become a werewolf and wiped my own memory?'

"Really? That's amazing!" She said. Ginny tucked a strand of loose ginger hair behind her ear and smiled brightly.

Her smile inspired him to try to explain what had happened. After all, if anybody would understand loss of memories, she would, right?

"Look, Ginny, something happened to me a few nights ago. When I was working on Sapespeck, I was attacked, and..." He fell silent, unsure how to continue.

Her eyes widened. "What?!" She whispered. Ginny glanced around them, then took a step closer. "Are you ok? What happened?"

"Right after I finished my work on the 25th, I felt this massive pain in my head." He pointed to the front of his skull. "It felt like someone was cutting away with a knife at my...at my me. Ever since then, I've been having these horrific dreams every night, dreams that I'm not myself, that I'm lying there unconscious in front of me...this isn't making any sense to you, is it."

Her face darkened, becoming unsettlingly austere. "Colin, that sounds really serious. I... You need to talk to someone. What you're describing? Those are symptoms of possession. "

He froze, paling rapidly.

"P-possession? Are you sure? But I didn't touch anything magical besides my wand, and nothing strange has happened to me during my dreams. The only odd thing going on is..." His eyes widened. "I've been missing memories."

Ginny shook her head. "I'm not an expert on how possession works…" Her expression grew colder, "just how it feels. And if you've been missing memories, then it's definitely a lot bigger than nightmares."

"I know. As soon as the feast ends, I'm heading to Madam Pomfrey."

"Pomfrey?! Go to Professor Mcgonagall! Or Slughorn!"

"And tell them what, exactly?" Colin snapped. "That I'm having dreams and my head hurts? Look, I'm going to go to Pomfrey first and see what she says and then, if she actually thinks there's something dangerous, then I'll tell the Headmistress."

She looked sceptical, but shrugged. "Fine, but let me know, ok? And if you ever need anything..." She absently raised a hand to the silver crucifix charm hanging delicately by her neck.

Colin's wand flicked through two complex motions and he grinned as a green mark appeared in the air near her.

"If I need ssomething, all I musst do is whissper."

She smiled. "You got it."

The train's harsh whistle suddenly sounded, startling the two.

"I'm sorry, but I'm not going to be able to sit with you on the train," Colin said sheepishly. "Draco wants me to report in. Something about the summer research. You understand."

Ginny nodded. "No worries. I'll see you at the banquet?"

"See you then."

XxX

September 1, 1993, 12 pm

Voldemort pulled back from his worktable, hands flicking in quick motions and extinguishing a handful of golden sparks. He almost had the spell that time, if it hadn't been for a burst of emotion from the other side of the bond. If he had had a few more seconds...he laughed sharply. Lack of his ritual seals would just make the whole process more fun. Anyway, his concentration was starting to flicker. A break was warranted.

After a quick meal, he returned to his worktable and closed his eyes briefly before quietly speaking a word from a language no modern lexicographer would recognize, calling up a faint yellow mist. As he watched, the mist organized itself into a series of hundreds of small interlocking circles, two of which faintly pulsed. With another word, the darkened circles vanished and the two glowing circles expanded to cover the entire table. He peered closer at the circles and curled his index finger. The yellow vanished to reveal hundreds of interlocking black words which seemed to be borrowed from every written language. With a tsk, he pulled out a line of connected characters from a section written mostly in kanji and read them over carefully.

"Hyōmen ni yotte, kokoro to kokoro no setsuzoku...Ah." He sighed. Even after 9 years of perfecting the ritual, he still managed to make the most idiotic of grammar errors. Really, it reflected badly on him. Anyway, the change was reasonably simple, all it would take was a few minor edits to the ritual. His wand flicked a few times, spinning out new kanji to replace the old before reading over his new handiwork.

"Kokoro to kokoro no setsuzoku, hitsuyōna toki ni yowai o miru koto o kanō ni suru kyōryokuna."

That should solve the pesky problem he had had two years ago with reading the child's emotions and thoughts. With another flick of his wand, the characters were covered by the yellow circles again. With another flick, the bright circles rejoined the dark ones. A moment later, Voldemort raised his wand.

"Aldaketak sartzea etenik gabe eta egonkortasuna zaintzeko."

He would have preferred not to speak aloud for magic of any sort, but ritual magic of this sort was dangerous enough to require his full concentration and any help the mechanisms of his superiors could give him. Anyway, his wards would prevent any sort of magical scrying and anyone who did look in would merely see an old woman muttering in Basque to herself. A totally normal activity for someone with Spanish ancestry, like Mrs. Babbage.

As the spell took effect, both circles glowed and he felt a slight pull at his magic. A moment later, he felt a presence at the back of his mind. When he pushed on the presence, it yielded, and he fell through to an entirely different mind. After catching just a few snatches of thought, he grinned and sent himself back through to his own mind. Out of all the justifications he gave for being a Dark Lord, he couldn't deny that the sheer thrill of a plan coming together was at the top of the list. Harry James Potter-Evans-Verres would soon know the dangers of trying to eliminate someone of his caliber.

A/N: So, as you can probably tell, the magic system is going to be a lot more fleshed out here. A lot more. Those who wish to translate the ritual segments and the Basque are welcome to. It will come back in the plot.

Meanwhile, I have to give serious thanks to kittykatrosetta for her aid with the Ginny segments of the chapter. The dialogue would have been far worse without her.

The next chapter, Re-entry, should be out before the 18th of October, and hopefully by the 11th.

Please review!

Chapter 5: Re-entry

One of the flaws of even the most competent bureaucracies when not all information is automatically logged is that, at some point, a lower level employee has to decide whether to pass information up the chain to their superiors. Normally, this is good; it keeps the higher-ups from becoming overwhelmed by unnecessary information. However, at times, it means crucial pieces of the puzzle fall through the cracks. On September 1st, 1993, Professor Remus J. Lupin performed the standard magical nullification spell to deal with an unfortunate buildup of magical energy in one of the compartments on the Hogwarts Express, caused by what, for all intents and purposes, appeared to be an outburst of accidental magic from one of the second years. A spell so standard, in fact, that he had almost forgotten about the entire incident a few months later.

Approximately 10 hours later, Professor Horace Slughorn used the same spell to nullify a Slytherin first year's accidental magic. 2 hours later, the event faded into the back of his mind. Within those 12 hours, Hogwarts' best chance to prevent the events of the next year had vanished.

This illustrates the importance of efficient information systems logs in a magical security system. Events such as that of 1993 would not have happened under proper supervision.

-Auror Handbook, Edition 49(Published 1999), Chapter IV: Effective Security Systems

XxX

September 1st, 1993, 12 pm

"Phoenix's egg."

The wall on the side of the Headmistress's office slid open, and Harry strode through the passageway, shaking his head to clear the reverberations of the magical passphrase. Once he reached the inside room, he turned to the right wall, stepped forward three steps, and pointed his wand at the passageway. Normally, he wouldn't activate Dumbledore's secondary protection magicks when he might need to call Hermione for help, but these experiments were far from a normal day's.

"Phoenix reborn."

An orange haze shot out of a sigil painted on the doorpost of the passageway, sealing the entire chambers in a magical stasis field and preventing anything, physical or magical, from entering or leaving the room unless it was specially keyed into the spell. A few seconds later, the field glowed a soft blue and began to magically ventilate the room by switching air inside the field with air outside it. Harry dearly wanted to know how much power that kind of spell took and if it was feasible for a third year to learn, but the unbreakable vow had stopped any sort of research into that area of magic. Quite sensibly, to be fair, as while he didn't know the potential consequences of messing up a time-space stasis spell, he imagined the results would be...catastrophic.

Harry pulled a small lump of steel from his pocket and set it down next to a notebook and dictation quill left there from the last experiment. He concentrated on visualizing a long glass tube, and touched his wand to the lump. A few seconds later, the steel was transfigured. Step one, complete.

Next, he visualized a loop of thread and transfigured the glass into the thread. A prior series of experiments involving magical items and enchanting transfigured objects had confirmed that, in some sense, magic recognized a transfigured item as two things: the item it currently was, and the item that it was connected to by use of some magic and visualization to connect Source and Form. It was time to test one of the corollaries of that hypothesis. With a conscious mental effort, Harry cut off the magical connection between Object:'Steel Lump' and Form: 'Glass cylinder', careful to sustain the transfiguration keeping the thread from morphing back into the cylinder. The thread seemed to shimmer once or twice as he broke the connection, and once took on a slightly glassy sheen, but eventually returned to normal.

Once the thread seemed to have stabilized, Harry broke the transfiguration on the thread. It abruptly flickered back into a glass tube, but something seemed...strange about it. He stepped over to the cylinder and gingerly picked it up, but it remained stable, weighing approximately the right amount. He turned back to the notebook and began speaking.

"Test 204a result: Transfiguration by connection breaking appears to be permanent, at least physically. Something appears off about the result. Further examination required."

He faced the cylinder again and raised his wand.

"Crystferrium!"

The spell extended outwards, and Harry could feel his magic take hold of the glass, beginning to reshape it into steel, when his magic abruptly failed. His eyes widened and he flicked his wand again.

"Locomotor Crystal!"

Again, the magic extended outwards and seemed to partially catch on the cylinder before failing. Harry's eyes widened. What the hell was going on? There was no reason that the glass shouldn't be responding, unless... He grinned, then laughed sharply. His wand went up again.

"Locomotor Ferrous!"

The cylinder twitched once or twice, then slowly rose into the air. Harry's jaw dropped and he started chuckling. It seemed that this method, while time consuming, certainly had...fun effects. He definitely needed to record this result.

"Test 204b result: Transfiguration by connection breaking preserves the magical identification of an object while modifying its physical properties. This physical modification appears to be permanent. Further research is required."

He turned back to the cylinder, but the stasis field flashed once, warning him of an approaching visitor. He turned back to the front door and saw Hermione waiting outside the field, tapping her foot impatiently, her arms folded over her chest. Harry shrugged apologetically then twisted his wand slightly.

"Phoenix's flight!"

The field flashed once and Hermione appeared on the other side, orange light cascading off of her as the field accepted her in. She brushed off a few lingering sparks, body moving gracefully. Harry's eyes widened slightly, mind momentarily taken from research by the realization that Hermione had indeed gone a ways through puberty.

She noticed his slightly widened eyes and grinned.

"While I can't say this isn't nice for my self esteem, I did want to see what you were researching. It's not like you to vanish so suddenly this close to the new year." A bit of concern tinged her voice.

He nodded and turned slightly to face the cylinder.

"Accio cylinder!"

He caught the cylinder deftly. A moment later, he turned back to Hermione.

"Try summoning this glass cylinder from me by identifying it by its element, if you would. "

She nodded confusedly.

"Ok, though I don't see why that matters...Accio glass!"

It seemed to twitch slightly, almost invisibly, but failed to move otherwise. Her eyes widened.

"You developed an anti-summoning charm?"

Harry grinned.

"Oh, this goes a good deal deeper than that. Try to use a glass-targeting spell, if you would."

Her eyes widened and she flicked her wrist.

"Locomotor Crystal!"

The cylinder failed to move. Hermione froze, processing the new information. There were currently two possibilities. Either, Harry had managed to derive multiple unknown countercharms, or...she gasped.

"You figured out how to change an object's magical identification, didn't you."

Harry smiled.

"Not exactly. I figured out how to permanently change its physical identification while preserving its magical identification. Behold...Transfiguration 2.0."

XxX

September 1st, 1993, 5 pm.

The train gradually glided to a stop and Colin quickly stepped off. If he wanted to make it back from Madam Pomfrey's in time for the Evening Feast, he'd need to hurry. Especially given whatever it was that had happened on the train. He wasn't even sure how to describe it, it just felt like the entire world outside his car had skipped forward a few seconds, while everyone inside the car had remained in the same position. Was that possession? Was Ginny right? As he reached the carriages, he hopped into the first one available. The moment he got inside, the carriage took off at a brisk pace, its mysterious driver seeming to sense Colin's agitation. He was glad about that, at least. He didn't want to have to talk to anybody else until he was certain he wasn't going to somehow be the vehicle for some Dark Lord's plans.

A few minutes later, the carriage pulled up to the castle and Colin stepped out. As he approached the entrance, the Headmistress seemed to appear from thin air near him.

"Mr. Creevey, we have some new security procedures this year because of what has happened in prior years. I was going to wait til more students arrived, but seeing as you're a few minutes ahead of them I will tell you now."

Her wand flicked once, and a sheet of moving water blurred into visibility from atop the entrance.

"Due to the generosity of certain concerned parents and the ingenuity of certain of our own students, we have been able to procure a permanent segment of the Thief's Downfall. Any student entering Hogwarts from outside the grounds will be required to pass through the water to be granted entrance."

Colin's eyes widened.

"What does the waterfall do, headmistress?"

Her tone changed, becoming more like that of the teacher she once was.

"The Thief's Downfall is an ancient magical device, created by wizards centuries ago. It's water removes all magical concealment, ends all compulsion, and breaks all illusions. Until this year, it was in the deepest vaults of Gringotts, protecting the possessions of the Noble Houses of Britain."

Colin relaxed. Even if he was possessed, this would break that possession. He would be himself again.

"So, how do I do this, headmistress? Do I just walk through the water?"

She nodded and her eyes glittered with suppressed mirth.

"Yes. Though, I must say, it's not often I see a student incredibly eager about removing deceptions."

Coling laughed sheepishly and stepped through the water. It parted over his shoulders, somehow still refreshing despite the already brisk day. Once he left the sheet fully, his body dried instantly. That was a nice feature. He calmly stepped forward into the halls, feeling calmer than he had in almost a week. He hadn't been possessed. Whatever these dreams and missing memories were, they weren't something too bad.

XxX

September 1st, 1993, 5:30 pm

Voldemort looked out at the station, mentally marking down every student who would be important for the coming year. The third years had Hogsmeade visits now, which would be an ideal time to implant low level compulsions were it not for the Thief's Downfall. Instead, he'd need to be quite a bit more subtle to get around that problem. Thus came his newest set of projects. The research relating to the graveyard event he'd been able to recover from the Unspeakables he'd captured had certainly been useful. Without it, he couldn't have been certain about any of his initial moves. However, with it, his opening was all but trivial. His hands twitched three times, and a group of 6 green lights appeared in the air before flying off into the distance towards the castle. He felt his energy drain slightly as each settled into place. A moment later, he turned back towards his house, satisfied. It was time to truly begin.

A/N: Have some more magic system research, I insist! The magical aliasing trick isn't quite as powerful as it might seem, there are some downsides to using it which will become apparent shortly.

Please review!